# **MATTHEW REEDS**

# Software Developer

# **GET IN TOUCH!**



(615) 389 - 1610



mattlreeds@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/mreeds



https://github.com/MReeds



mreeds.github.io

# PERSONAL PROFILE

When I first heard about the opportunity to lead a career in software development I was working in a team with four other managers to ensure the upmost quality of our products and to deliver the finest service to our guests. I started searching for new opportunities that would challenge me and better my future.

When I discovered Nashville Software School I always saw myself pursuing a career in the technical field but I never quite knew where to start. I saw NSS as the initial step towards lifelong learning and a way to build a better future for both myself and my future family.

As I have been learning to write code in order to build useful applications I have found that finding the solution to a problem is one of the most rewarding feelings you could experience. The immense amount of patience and dedication it requires to reach the appropriate outcome is a true skill that takes time to master. Beginning down the life long road of learning code has truly been a gratifying endeavor thusfar.

# **ACADEMIC BACKGROUND**

#### **Nashville Software School**

Full-Stack Software Development Bootcamp

#### **Volunteer State Community College**

- Graduated Magna Cum Laude
- National Society of Leadership and Success
- Dean's List

#### **PROJECTS**

# **Personal Project**

# Reassurance | https://github.com/MReeds/FrontEnd-Capstone

Created a React based app designed to accompany a user while reading through scripture in the Bible and record a special verse that made a lasting impression on them.

- A user can record data including the ability to tag the saved verse with an associated emotion which updates the state within the verse component and adds it as a new object to the database.
- Once you have created a verse and tagged it with an emotion you can filter based on an emotion which updates state and presents filtered data using the UseEffect hook.
- Full CRUD functionality to comment on individual verses to supply context or notate thoughts.
- Designed the data architecture using DB Diagrams
- Created a mock up for the site using Mogups.
- Navbar, Sign-In/Register and card design was created using Reactstrap.
- Materialize was used for other styling elements such as the buttons and text boxes.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Nashville Software School**

# Full-Stack Software Developer | January 2020 - present

Six-month accelerated program focusing on full-stack development projects in a technical environment.

Utilized technologies like the following to create increasingly elaborate CRUD applications:

- HTML5 for structure and presentation
- CSS3 for format and layout
- JavaScript to interact with the user and create dynamic pages
- React.js for reusable UI components
- Git and GitHub for version-control
- Figma for designing UI/UX mockup designs
- DB Diagrams for designing databases
- Emphasized pair-programming and team oriented sprints to complete CRUD applications using external API's and REST API's via JSON Server.
- Project sprints included issue tracking, user stories and team retrospectives.

#### **NSS Group Project**

**Nutshell** | https://github.com/nss-day-cohort-38/react-nutshell-purple-turf-storm

Worked in a team of four to create a React based social dashboard that posted user specific data including personal events, tasks, news and a message board.

- Responsibilities included building the message board feature for the application
- Full CRUD functionality and user specific views and interactions with the 'Edit' and 'Delete' buttons.
- Created the ReadMe documentation that provided information such as the required installations and steps to setup the application on a local machine.
- Technologies used: React, React Router Dom, Moment.js, CSS

## **EXPERIENCE CONTINUED**

#### The Melting Pot

**Restaurant Manager** | January 2019 - December 2019

The Melting Pot is the original fondue restaurant where guests can enjoy several fondue cooking styles and a variety of unique entrees, salads, and unforgettable desserts.

- Ensured guest satisfaction by maintaining a high standard among all service staff
- Ensured all employees maintained safe food and allergy handling practices
- · Maintained a safe working and guest environment to reduce the risk of injury and accidents
- · Well-rounded with Microsoft tools such as Word, PowerPoint and Excel. As well as maintaining expenses through QuickBooks Pro
- Managed over 50 employees jobs ranging throughout the Front of House and Back of House
- Led fondue training classes that guided employees from the start of service to the final farewell
- Managed and led the hiring process which included orientation, tax documentation, on boarding and bank account reference information for every employee
- · Supervised and maintained a group of team-leads instructing new staff and upholding company policies
- Oversaw front of house personnel to maintain adequate staffing and minimize overtime
- Led meetings to discuss points of praise and areas for growth for the service staff

#### **Bartender** | February 2018 - January 2019

- Maximize guest satisfaction and beverage Sales through guest service excellence, cost-effective bar management and inventive cocktails
- Provided bar patrons with superior service and an enjoyable, memorable experience at Nashville Melting Pot
- · Excelled at up-selling guests from shelf to premium brands and high-margin signature cocktails
- Respectively leveraged interpersonal skills and drink-making knowledge to cultivate a loyal clientele
- Reinvented classic cocktails, providing a new culinary spin on mojitos, manhattans, martinis
- · Aided in training on improvements to bar inventory management, precision pouring and waste reduction

#### Server - Lead | January 2016- January 2018

- Provided genuine hospitality and quality customer service to large parties of up to 50+ guests on a daily basis
- Took orders, presented and explained specials, offered information, and made suggestions about the menu
- · Made personalized suggestion for wine, cocktails, and four course meals with professional appearance and mannerism
- Personally prepped, delivered and prepared the cheese fondue appetizer for guests with professionalism
- Maintained clean and sanitary work areas and tables
- Worked with servers as a team to execute large party dining experiences reaching up to 50+ people
- Anticipated and fulfilled guest needs and requests
- Followed proper plate presentation with emphasis on detail

#### Server Assistant - Lead | February 2015 - January 2016

- Led team of four server assistants
- · Responsible for training new hires and preparing them for high volume weekends and special events
- Organized and prepared services for special events
- Coordinated restaurant work flow with top management and servers
- Responsible for problem solving and special requests

